# Klaus Holder

klausholder@alumni.harvard.edu � (203) 710-3494 � Brookline, MA

## **SUMMARY**

Support and Optimization Engineer with 5 years of experience managing broad I.T. needs of multiple schools. Key strengths include troubleshooting building and user technology, programming novel automation solutions to expand role capacity, budgeting tech purchases, contract and vendor relations, client-facing communications, and cross-functional team management. Additional experience with C#, web development, PowerShell, GAM(Google Apps Manager), and Python scripting has helped me excel in my current roles.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# UP Education Network, Support Engineer

Sep. 2018 – Present Boston, MA

- Manage technology at our 3 Boston schools supporting over 300 staff and 2000 Students.
  - o Search for and create automation opportunities to expand role capacity.
  - o Quickly and efficiently support 300 staff through ZenDesk's ticketing system.
  - o Programmed Arduino Boards to auto-enroll Chromebooks.
- o Created Azure printer apps across all schools to automatically push applications to end-users via Microsoft Intune.
  - o Introduced GAM scripting to workflow greatly reducing time for recurring GAdmin tasks.
  - o Regularly repair and maintain staff laptops, Chromebooks, iPads, and other classroom technology.
  - o Oversee technology upgrades across schools and interface with vendors to ensure project completion.
- Hire and train interns for our IT tasks, leading them through our summer school setup tasks.

## Independent Contractor, Support Engineer

Oct. 2022 - Jan. 2023 Boston, MA

- Migrated company's workspace from Google to Microsoft.
- Provided remote and on-site IT support.

Dr. An T. Phan, MD, Office Administrator

Jan. 2018 – Jan. 2019 Boston, MA

# Freelance Web Developer, Front-End Developer

- May 2016 Dec. 2017 Quincy, MA
- Architected solutions that leveraged front-end development techniques.
- Scheduled design sessions and created prototypes for clients.

# Digital Media Academy, Java Instructor

June 2014 – Aug. 2014 *Cambridge, MA* 

■ Taught over 50 students the fundamentals of object-oriented programming via Java.

## **EDUCATION**

Harvard University May 2017 ALB, Sciences

Cambridge, MA

## **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

- Skills: CLI; Powershell; C#, CRM Software Zendesk; Remote Technical Support; IT project management; Cisco Meraki MDM and Network Management; simple SQL; bash scripts; IT Documentation; Asset Databases; Workflow Management; G-Suite Admin; Slack; Zoom; GApps Script; Adobe Photoshop
- Interests: Ludology, hobbyist C# game dev, Metal Gear Solid, Magic the Gathering, fantasy novels